Guide to the Montana Wheat Research and Marketing Committee Records 1967-1988
Montana Historical Society
Montana Wheat Research and Marketing Committee Records
1967-1988
Montana Historical Society Archives
RS 174
Montana Wheat Research and Marketing Committee
1.2 linear feet of shelf space
These records (1967-1988) of the Montana Wheat Research and Marketing Committee consist of general correspondence, financial reports, minutes, reports, speeches, and miscellany.
The Montana Wheat Research and Marketing Committee was established in 1967 as the advisory committee for the Division of Wheat Research and Marketing. The Division was responsible for conducting research into all phases of wheat culture, production, and marketing. The Committee, consisting of 20 members, advised the Division on policy and also functioned as the research and development arm. The program was financed by a special tax on wheat.
These records consist of general correspondence, which includes clippings and miscellany mailed to committee members for their information; financial reports; minutes, which include proposals and exhibits provided to committee members; reports; speeches; and miscellany.
The collection is arranged by series.
Collection open for research.
Acquisition information is available upon request.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the Montana Historical Society Archives catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search under these terms.
Agriculture and state--Montana; Wheat--Montana; Wheat farmers--Montana
Montana; Agriculture; Government and Politics
Detailed Description of the Collection
The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection
- General correspondence
  - Committee members [correspondents include Robert Bastrup, Norris E. Hanford, V. J. Thuesen, Lloyd Mosdal, Glenn Moore, Jack Lang, George Skarda, Harold Nelson, and J. James Christianson], 1967-1988 (Box-folder 1 / 1-4)
  - Miscellaneous [correspondents include Northern Montana College, Montana State University, Western Wheat Associates, U.S. Department of Agriculture, Montana Department of Agriculture, Montana WIFE, Taiwan Flour Mills Association], 1969-1988 (Box-folder 1 / 5)
- Financial records
  - Financial reports, 1968-1988 (Box-folder 1 / 6-8)
  - Ledger, 1968-1972 (Box-folder VOL / 1)
- Minutes
  - Montana Wheat Research and Marketing Committee [includes reports and exhibits submitted to members at meetings], 1967-1988 (Box-folder 1 / 9-16)
- Reports
  - Executive Secretary: monthly reports, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 1 / 17)
  - Great Falls Chamber of Commerce Agriculture Committee Tour to Agriculture Research Station, Lethbridge, Alberta, 1968 (Box-folder 1 / 18)
  - Synopsis and Update of Staggers Rail Act of 1980, 1981 (Box-folder 1 / 19)
- Speeches
  - George Skarda to Farmer's Union, Moore, Montana, 1968 (Box-folder 1 / 20)
- Miscellany
  - Assessments of wheat, 1967-1971 (Box-folder 1 / 21)
  - Miscellaneous (includes memorandum of understanding, ARM rule adoption, and resolution), 1974-1980 (Box-folder 1 / 22)